In this video, I want
在这个视频中 我想
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to start telling you about how
开始向你介绍
we represent Neural Networks,
我们该如何表示神经网络
in other words how we represent
换句话说 当我们在
our hypotheses or how
运用神经网络时
we represent our model when using your Neural Networks.
我们该如何表示我们的假设或模型
Neural Networks were developed at
神经网络是在模仿
simulating neurons or networks of neurons in the brain.
大脑中的神经元或者神经网络时发明的
So, to explain the hypotheses
因此 要解释如何表示
representation. Let's start by
模型假设 我们先来看单个
looking at what a single
神经元在大脑中
neuron in the brain looks like.
是什么样的
Your brain and mine is jam-packed
我们的大脑中充满了
full of neurons like these
这样的神经元
and neurons are cells in
神经元是大脑中的细胞
the brain and the two
其中有两点
things to draw attention to are
值得我们注意
that first that the
一是神经元有
neuron has a cell body
像这样的细胞主体
like so and moreover, the
二是神经元有
neuron has a number of
一定数量的
input wires and these are
输入神经
called the dendrites who think of
这些输入神经叫做树突
them as input wires and
可以把它们想象成输入电线
these receive inputs from other
它们接收来自其他
locations and the neuron
神经元的信息
also has an output wire called the axon.
神经元的输出神经叫做轴突
And this output wire
这些输出神经
is what it uses to send
是用来
signal to other neurons
给其他神经元传递信号
or to send messages to other neurons.
或者传送信息的
So, at a simplistic level, what
简而言之
a neuron is is a computational
神经元是一个计算单元
unit that gets a number
它从输入神经接受一定数目的信息
of inputs through its input wires, does some computation.
并做一些计算
and then it sends outputs, via its
然后将结果通过它的
axon to other nodes
轴突传送到其他节点
or other neurons in the brain.
或者大脑中的其他神经元
Here's an illustration of a group of neurons.
下面是一组神经元的示意图
The way that neurons communicate
神经元利用微弱的电流
with each other is with little pulses of electricities.
进行沟通
They're also called spikes, but they're just means of little pulse of electricity.
这些弱电流也称作动作电位 其实就是一些微弱的电流
So, here's one neuron and what
所以如果
it does is if it
神经元想要
wants to send a message,
传递一个消息
what it does is it sends
它就会就通过它的轴突
the little pulse of electricity via its
发送一段微弱电流
axon to some difference
给其他神经元
neuron and here this axon.
这就是轴突
There is this open wire.
这里是一条
Connects to the input wire or
连接到输入神经
connects to the dendrite of this
或者连接另一个神经元
second neuron over here, which
树突的神经
then accepts this incoming message
接下来这个神经元接收这条消息
does some computation and may
做一些计算
in turn decide to send
它有可能会反过来将
out its O messages on its
在轴突上的
axon to other neurons.
自己的消息传给其他神经元
And this is the process by
这就是所有
which all human thought
人类思考的模型：
happens as these neurons doing
我们的神经元把
computations and passing messages
自己的收到的消息进行计算
to other neurons as a
并向其他神经元
result of what other inputs they've got.
传递消息
And by the way, this is how
顺便说一下 这也是
our senses and our muscles work as well.
我们的感觉和肌肉运转的原理
If you want to move one
如果你想活动一块肌肉
of your muscles, the way that
就会触发一个神经元
works is that a neuron may
给你的肌肉
send these pulses of electricities
发送脉冲
to your muscle and that causes
并引起
your muscles to contract and your
你的肌肉收缩
eyes - if some
如果一些感官
sensor like your eye
比如说眼睛
wants to send a message to
想要给大脑传递
your brain, what it does
一个消息
is it sends its pulses of
那么它就像这样发送
electricity to a neuron in your brain like so.
电脉冲给大脑的
In a neural network, or
在一个神经网络里
rather in an artificial neural
或者说在我们在电脑上
network that we implement in
实现的人工神经网络里
a computer, we're going to
我们将使用
use a very simple model
一个非常简单的模型
of what a neuron does.
来模拟神经元的工作
We're going to model a neuron as just a logistic unit.
我们将神经元模拟成一个逻辑单元
So, when I draw a yellow
当我画一个这样的
circle like that, you should hink of
黄色圆圈时 你应该
that as playing a
把它想象成
role analogous to maybe the
作用类似于
body of a neuron, and
神经元的东西
we then feed the neuron a
然后我们通过
few inputs via its dendrites or
它的树突或者说它的输入神经
its input wires and the neuron does some computation
传递给它一些信息 然后神经元做一些计算
and output some value on
并通过它的输出神经
this output wire or in
即它的轴突
a biological neuron that sorts
输出计算结果
the axon and whenever I
当我画一个
draw a diagram like this, what
像这样的图表时
this means is that this represents
就表示对h(x)的计算
a computations of, you know, h of x equals 1
h(x)等于1除以
over 1 + e to
1加e的
the negative theta transpose x where, as
负θ转置乘以 x
usual, x and theta
通常  x和θ
are our parameter vectors like so.
是我们的参数向量
So, this is a very simple maybe
这是一个简单的模型
a vastly over simplified model of
甚至说是一个过于简单的
the computation that the neuron
模拟神经元的模型
does where it gets the
它被输入 x1  x2和 x3
number of inputs, x1, x2,
然后输出一些
x3 and it outputs some value computed like so.
类似这样的结果
When I draw a neural network,
当我绘制一个神经网络时
usually I draw only the
通常我只绘制
input nose x1, x2, x3,
输入节点 x1  x2  x3
sometimes when it's useful to do so.
但有时也可以这样做：
I draw an extra node for x zero.
我增加一个额外的节点 x0
This x zero node is
这个 x0 节点
sometimes called the bias unit
有时也被称作偏置单位
or the bias neuron but because
或偏置神经元 但因为
x0 is already equal to 1.
x0 总是等于1
Sometimes, I draw with it, sometimes
所以有时候 我会画出它
I won't just depending on whether
有时我不会画出
there's more the rotationally convenient for that example.
这取决于它是否对例子有利
Finally, one last
现在来讨论
bit of terminology when we
最后一个关于
talk about neural networks, sometimes
神经网络的术语
we'll say that this
有时我们会说
is a neuron - an
这是一个神经元
artificial neuron  with a sigmoid or a logistic
一个有s型函数或者逻辑函数作为激励函数的
activation function.
人工神经元
So this activation function in the neuronetro
在神经网络术语中
terminology, this is just
激励函数只是对类似非线性
another term for that
函数g(z)的另一个术语称呼
function for that non-linearity g
g(z)等于
of z, equals 1
1除以1
over 1 plus e to the negative z.
加e的-z次方
And whereas so far
到目前为止
I've been calling theta the parameters
我一直称θ为
of the model are mostly continued
模型的参数
to use that terminology to conjugate
以后大概会继续将这个术语与
to the parameters, but the neural networks.
“参数”相对应 而不是与神经网络
In the neural networks literature and
在关于神经网络的文献里
sometimes you might hear people
有时你可能会看到人们
talk about weights of a
谈论一个模型的权重
model and weights just means
权重其实和
exactly the same thing as
模型的参数
parameters of the model.
是一样的东西
But almost to use the terminology
在视频中
parameters in these videos,
我会继续使用“参数”这个术语
but sometimes you may hear others use the weights terminology.
但有时你可能听到别人用“权重”这个术语
So, this little
这个小圈
diagram represents a single neuron.
代表一个单一的神经元
What a neural network is
神经网络其实就是
Is just a proof of
这些不同的神经元
these different neurons strung together.
组合在一起的集合
Concretely, here we have
具体来说 这里是我们的
input units x1, x2, and x3
输入单元 x1  x2和 x3
and once again,
再说一次
sometimes can draw this
有时也可以画上
extra node x0 or sometimes
额外的节点 x0
not. So, I just draw that in here.
我把 x0 画在这了
And here we have
这里有
three neurons, which I
3个神经元
have written, you know, a(2)1, a(2)2 and
我在里面写了a(2)1 a(2)2
a(2)3 around top bottles indices
和a(2)3
later and once again,
然后再次说明
we can if we want
我们可以在这里
adding this a0 and
添加一个a0
add an extra bias unit there.
和一个额外的偏度单元
It always outputs the value of 1.
它的值永远是1
Then finally we have this
最后 我们在
third node at the final
最后一层有第三个节点
layer, and it's this
正是这第三个节点
third node that opens the value
输出
that the hypotheses h of x computes.
假设函数h(x)计算的结果
To introduce a bit
再多说一点关于
more terminology in a neural
神经网络的术语
network, the first layer, this
网络中的第一层
is also called the input
也被称为输入层
layer because this is where
因为我们在这一层
we input our features, x1 x2 x3.
输入我们的特征项 x1 x2 x3
The final layer is
最后一层
also called the output layer
也称为输出层
because that layer has
因为这一层的
the neuron - this one over
神经元—我指的这个
here - that outputs the
输出
final value computed by a
假设的最终计算结果
hypotheses and then layer
中间的两层
two in between, this is called the hidden layer.
也被称作隐藏层
The term hidden layer isn't a
隐藏层不是一个
great terminology, but the
很合适的术语 但是
intuition is that, you know, in
直觉上我们知道
supervised learning where you
在监督学习中
get to see the inputs, and you get to see the correct outputs.
你能看到输入 也能看到正确的输出
Whereas the hidden layer are values you
而隐藏层的值
don't get to observe in the training set.
你在训练集里是看不到的
If it's not x and it's not y and so we call those hidden.
它的值不是 x 也不是y 所以我们叫它隐藏层
and later on we'll see neural
稍后我们会看到神经网络
networks with more than
可以有不止一个的
one hidden layer, but in
隐藏层 但在
this example we have one
这个例子中 我们有一个
input layer, layer 1; one hidden
输入层—第1层 一个隐藏层—
layer, layer 2; and one output layer, layer 3.
第2层 和一个输出层—第3层
But basically anything that isn't
但实际上任何
an input layer and isn't a
非输入层或非输出层的层
output layer is called a hidden layer.
就被称为隐藏层
So, I
接下来
want to be really clear
我希望你们明白神经网络
about what this neural network is doing.
究竟在做什么
Let's step through the computational
让我们逐步分析
steps that are embodied
这个图表所呈现的
by this, represented by this diagram.
计算步骤
To explain the specific computations
为了解释这个神经网络
represented by a neural network,
具体的计算步骤
here's a little bit more notation.
这里还有些记号要解释
I'm going to use a superscript
我要使用a上标(j)
j subscript i to denote
下标i表示
the activation of neuron i
第j层的
or of unit i in layer
第i个神经元或单元
j.  So concretely, this
具体来说 这里
a superscript 2 subscript 1
a上标(2) 下标1
does the activation of the
表示第2层的
first unit in layer 2,
第一个激励
in our hidden layer.
即隐藏层的第一个激励
And by activation, I just mean,
所谓激励(activation) 是指
you know, the value that is computed
由一个具体神经元读入
by and that is output by a specific.
计算并输出的值
In addition, our neural network
此外 我们的神经网络
is parametrized by these matrices,
被这些矩阵参数化
theta superscript j where
θ上标(j)
our theta j is going to
它将成为
be a matrix of waves
一个波矩阵
controlling the function mapping from
控制着
one layer, maybe the first
从一层 比如说从第一层
layer to the second layer or from the second layer to the third layer.
到第二层或者第二层到第三层的作用
So, here are the computations that are represented by this diagram.
所以 这就是这张图所表示的计算
This first hidden unit here,
这里的第一个隐藏单元
has its value computed as
是这样计算它的值的：
follows: is a a(2)1 is
a(2)1等于
equal to the sigmoid
s函数
function, or the sigmoid activation function
或者说s激励函数
also called the logistic activation function,
也叫做逻辑激励函数
applied to this sort
作用在这种
of linear combination of its inputs.
输入的线性组合上的结果
And then this second hidden
第二个隐藏单元
unit has this activation
等于s函数作用在这个
value computed as sigmoid of this.
线性组合上的值
And similarly, for this
同样 对于第三个
third hidden unit, it's computed by that formula.
隐藏的单元 它是通过这个公式计算的
So here, we have three
在这里 我们有三个
input units and the three hidden units.
输入单元和三个隐藏单元
And so the dimension
这样一来
of theta one which the
参数矩阵控制了
matrix of parameters governing our
我们来自
mapping from all three input
三个输入单元
units, about three hidden units
三个隐藏单元的映射
theta 1 is going to
因此θ1的维数
be a 3,
将变成3
theta 1 is going to
θ1将变成一个
be a 3 by 4 dimensional
3乘4维的
matrix and more generally,
矩阵 更一般的
if a network has Sj
如果一个网络在第j
units and their j
层有sj个单元
and Sj + 1 units
在j+1层有
in their j + 1 then
sj+1个单元
the matrix theta j which
那么矩阵θ(j)
governs the function mapping from
即控制第j层到
layer j to layer j +
第j+1层映射
1 that we'll have to mention
的矩阵的
Sj + 1 by Sj + 1.
维度为s(j+1) * (sj+1)
Just be clear about this notation, right?
这里要搞清楚
This is S subscript j
这个是s下标j+1
+ 1 and that's S
而这个是
subscript j, and then
s下标j 然后
this whole thing, plus 1.
整体加上1
Of this whole thing, that's j + 1, okay?
整体加1 明白了吗
So that's S subscript j plus
所以θ(j)的维度是
1 plus, by So,
s(j+1)行 sj+1列
that's S subscript j plus
这里sj+1
1 by Sj
当中的1
+ 1 where as plus 1 is not part of the subscript.
不是下标的一部分
So, we talked about what
以上我们讨论了
the three hidden units do to compute their values.
三个隐藏单位是怎么计算它们的值
Finally, this last, the spinal in optimal
最后 在输出层
layer, we have one more
我们还有一个
units which computes h of
单元 它计算
x and that's equal, can
h(x)  这个也可以
also be written as a(3)1
写成a(3)1
and that's equal to this.
就等于后面这块
And you notice that I've
注意到我这里
written this with a superscript
写了个上标2
2 here because theta superscript
因为θ上标2
2 is the matrix of parameters,
是参数矩阵
or the matrix of weights that
或着说是权重矩阵 该矩阵
controls the function that maps
控制从第二层
from the hidden units, that
即隐藏层的3个单位
is the layer 2 units,
到第三层
to the 1 layer 3
的一个单元
unit that is the output
即输出单元
unit.
的映射
To summarize, what we've done
总之 以上我们
is shown how a picture
展示了像这样一张图是
like this over here defines
怎样定义
an artificial neural network which defines
一个人工神经网络的
a function h that maps
这个神经网络定义了函数h：
your x's input values to hopefully
从输入 x
to some space and provisions y?
到输出y的映射
And these hypotheses after parametrized
我将这些假设的参数
by parameters that I
记为大写的θ
am denoting with a capital
这样一来
theta so that as
不同的θ
we be vary theta we get different hypotheses.
对应了不同的假设
So we get different functions mapping
所以我们有不同的函数
say from x to y.   So
比如说从 x到y的映射
this gives us a mathematical
以上就是我们怎么
definition of how to
从数学上定义
represent the hypotheses in the neural network.
神经网络的假设
In the next few videos, what
在接下来的视频中
I'd like to do is give
我想要做的就是
you more intuition about what
让你对这些假设的作用
these hypotheses representations do, as
有更深入的理解
well as go through a
并且讲解几个例子
few examples and talk about how to compute them efficiently.
然后谈谈如何有效的计算它们